Previously on Ghost...
- Yas. what's up?
- When are you coming
- to get me?
- Soon. I promise.
We just gotta be strong together
no matter what. okay?
Find out who killed
that professor.
That's how we get Zeke
out from under all this.
You want me to wear a wire?
If you do.
I promise I can get them
to drop any criminal
investigation into you.
Yeah. okay.
This is a new Rollie?
Um... yeah.
I'll be right back. okay?
I hired that attorney
we talked about.
Who? The white dude?
Yeah. Saxe.
Look. he don't know it yet...
He's gonna help me
get you outta here.
Davis MacLean needs
a million dollars by tomorrow
to pay for Zeke's defense.
Absolutely fucking not.
I know you paid Davis
the million dollars today.
What am I 'posed to tell
my husband about another man
paying my nephew's
million-dollar bill?
Maybe tell him
I did what I needed to do
to protect our son.
Go get Ramirez' body.
What if it backs up on me. Ma?
You made your choice. Cane.
It is what it is.
You help me with this shit.
you'll level up in no time.
What I got to do?
I'll see your bitch ass
tomorrow. B.
And tell Tariq...
I be seeing him too.
The police theory is that
you paid Detective Ramirez
to kill Jabari Reynolds.
This is some bullshit.
Get out of my face with that.
Fuck. Zeke.
Do you think
Zeke actually did it?
Look. I know
he didn't do it. a'ight?
- How do you know?
- I gotta go.
This is the DA's office.
They want Zeke
to turn himself in.
What?
♪ They say this is
A big. rich town ♪
♪ I just come
From the poorest part ♪
♪ Bright lights. city life ♪
♪ I gotta make it
This is where it goes down ♪
♪ I just happen
To come up hard ♪
♪ Legal or illegal. baby
I gotta make it ♪
♪ I never took
A straight path nowhere ♪
♪ Life's full of twists
And turns. bumps and bruises ♪
♪ I live. I learn ♪
♪ I'm from that city full of
Yellow cabs and skyscrapers ♪
♪ It's hard to get a start
In these parts without paper ♪
♪ Homey. I grew up in hell
A block away from heaven ♪
♪ That corner every 15 minutes
They moving seven ♪
♪ Pure snow. bag it
Then watch it go ♪
♪ Occupational options
Get some blow or some hos ♪
♪ Shoot the ball or the strap
Learn to rap or to jack ♪
♪ Fuck it. man In the meantime ♪
♪ Go head and pump a pack ♪
♪ This my regal. royal flow
My James Bond bounce ♪
♪ That 007
That's 62 on my count ♪
♪ I'm an undercover liar
I lie under the covers ♪
♪ Look a bitch in the eyes ♪
♪ And tell her Baby. I love ya ♪
♪ You're my inspiration
You're my motivation ♪
♪ You're the reason that I'm
Moving with no hesitation ♪
♪ They say this is
A big. rich town ♪
♪ Yeah. I just come
From the poorest part ♪
♪ Bright lights. city life ♪
♪ I gotta make it
This is where it goes down ♪
♪ Oh. yeah. yeah ♪
♪ I just happen
To come up hard ♪
♪ Legal or illegal. baby
I gotta make it ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Whoa Everybody wants freedom ♪
♪ Everybody wants freedom Whoa ♪
♪ But they think I'm inhuman ♪
♪ Lock me up for no reason.
Whoa ♪
♪ And they got community ♪
♪ They wanna kill us
With impunity. whoa... ♪
Zeke. don't talk to
anyone on the inside.
Inmates will try and rat you out
to save their own ass. okay?
Just shut up and blend in.
We'll go in the back.
avoid the press.
Zeke. every moment
you're in there.
know I'm doing everything in
my power to get you out. okay?
I don't think you have
much control over this. Monet.
It's too late for all that.
Yo. I gotta go.
I'ma see you in class.
Wait. Hold on. just a second.
I'm almost done.
Good morning.
My client is here
to voluntarily turn himself in.
Detective Whitman
is expecting us.
Who's your client...
Where's he going?
I thought they was expecting us.
Jenny. what are you
doing here so bright and early?
Didn't think the ADA needed to
come out for a routine arrest.
especially when my client
is innocent.
Yes. well. that's why I'm here.
We won't be needing Mr. Cross
to turn himself in anymore.
as it turns out.
Oh. well. one more time.
Jenny. slowly?
- I'm free to go?
- You are free to go. Mr. Cross.
Then I think my client
deserves some answers at least.
- What changed since last night?
- Zeke is no longer a suspect.
There's been
some new developments.
We won't be holding
Mr. Cross at this time.
I'm sure your client
doesn't wanna be
in this precinct
any longer than he has to be.
Well. you heard her. Let's go.
I expect a full press briefing
to clear my client today.
I'll see what I can do.
Let me walk you out.
♪ ♪
See. I told you it was
nothing to worry about.
I knew they was gonna
find you innocent all along.
Don't change
that I'm radioactive
after that interview.
I might be free.
but I'm still fucked.
Who's gonna wanna draft me now?
Look. let me give you
a ride back to school.
Once this gets out
and the teams find out
that you're cleared. you'll be
back in the conversations.
I'm sure of that.
You cut me off back there.
That was to keep you
from telling that kid
something he could take back
to his accomplice.
You're like
a fucking broken record.
How long is he gon'
be your suspect?
Ramirez and Reynolds both
were killed with the same gun.
Ramirez's gun.
If Zeke was gonna
commit a crime.
why would he give you
Ramirez's PBA card?
He gave you the connection.
But it was still a connection.
The body that exonerates Cross
just mysteriously
shows up the day after
he shits his pants
on national TV.
You don't find
that fucking fishy?
No. 'cause Zeke
is not our only lead.
I've been reading
Jabari Reynolds' novel.
- His fucking novel?
- Yes.
- C'mon.
- A few of the locations
in the book matches up
to some of the Stansfield
landmarks.
- So what?
- Listen!
Are you gonna let me speak?
'Cause I do my job well.
Go ahead.
Reynolds' first novel...
It was inspired
by actual events.
His new book is about
some serious drug activity
that takes place on a campus
that more than resembles
Stansfield.
What if he got himself
into somethin'
that's not so fictional?
Yo. what's up with you?
You good?
Yeah. just a...
A little hung over.
But we gotta talk later though.
Heard about some dorm sweeps
for drugs.
Some of our customers
got pulled in.
Tariq. did you hear me?
Some of our customers
got pulled in by the cops.
Yeah. um... like you said.
we'll talk about
that shit later.
Right now we need to focus on
clearing everything outta here
and put everything
on the roof for now. okay?
Hey. yo. um. Cane...
He come around here
asking for me or looking for me
or anything like that?
No. why? What's going on?
Any of the Tejadas come around
asking where I am
or anything like that.
you don't know shit. okay?
Okay. yeah.
I-is everything good?
I'ma figure out.
Just stay away from Cane
and text me
if any of them come over here.
Mrs. Tejada.
I was actually gonna call you.
I've been making real headway.
Bitch. that's not why I called.
The cops know Zeke didn't do it.
so whatever you doin'.
stop right now... it's done.
Did they find a new suspect?
That's not your problem or mine.
They let him go.
That's all
the fuck that matters.
You know. you're the reason
why he's in this shit
in the first place.
I don't ever wanna
see your face again.
I don't wanna hear your name.
You stay the fuck
away from Zeke.
You stay away from me.
You keep your job.
You don't know me.
I don't know you.
and you don't know Zeke...
got it?
Yes. I-I understand.
Detectives.
what are you doing here?
We could use your help.
I think I've helped enough.
We don't have a right to ask.
but if you'd be willing
to help us at this time...
I don't think so.
You said it to me
you were law enforcement.
You took a oath.
Don't you wanna know
who killed Professor Reynolds?
We have the manuscript
he was workin' on.
All Whitman and I are asking
for you to do is read it.
Why did you wanna meet here?
Because I don't
trust myself around you
and those hotel rooms of yours.
And I need to talk
to you about Zeke.
I thought you turned him in
this morning.
We went to the precinct.
They told us they have
some recent developments.
and they didn't
want Zeke anymore.
So I took him back to school.
Did you have anything to do with
these recent developments.
Monet?
I handled the situation
without your money.
We don't need to fight
together anymore. Dante.
There's nothing to fight.
Ha. Wait a minute.
I'm pretty sure I was
the solution for a hot second.
Please don't make me out
to be the problem.
Look. it's not you. It's me.
I been making
some really big mistakes lately
like leaving our son
down at the precinct
while I'm off playing
princess with you.
- Hmm.
- I gotta get back to reality
and face my responsibilities
and stop all this
fairytale bullshit.
Okay.
But go back for how long. and...
I'm sorry. but to what reality?
I mean. your husband
may be inside.
but you are clearly
still in the life.
Those clothes you got on
didn't come from the bar
- that we're standing in.
- I got a plan to get out.
and it won't take long.
I am trying to give you
a choice. Monet.
You didn't have one
when you left Zeke
or when your husband went in.
but what if you could
decide what you want?
These aren't filed... yet.
I could set up your kids
with trust funds.
All your kids. not just Zeke.
And maybe then you could
choose the life you want.
Choose the man you want
instead of spending the life
you have running around
trying to keep your world
from falling apart.
Because that is not a life.
That is a ticking time bomb.
All you gotta do...
is sign.
Look. I don't need
a redo. Dante.
I know how to make
my own decisions.
and I'm not 16.
I know you're not 16 anymore.
Neither am I.
This... stop. This is too much.
This is too much.
You're too much right now.
Just go. please.
You know. you almost
lost Zeke this time. Nae-Nae.
How much do you wanna lose
before you make a better choice?
You know.
I'm not leaving New York
until you leave with me.
I know you think you got this.
but you can't handle this
by yourself.
Fuck.
Okay. what the hell
happened to you this morning?
You just disappeared.
I know. I'm sorry.
I... I forgot I had to
make an appointment.
I need to get an apartment
so I can get my sister.
There's a hearing tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Okay. that's really fast.
Do you need help?
No. It's fine.
You don't have to.
I know. I want to.
A'ight. Thank you.
All right!
Karma?
Uh. that wasn't in
last night's reading.
I know. I thought I'd keep
everyone on their toes.
But isn't this
- more theological than ethical?
- Perhaps.
Who can define karma for me?
Karma's the belief
in certain Indian religions
that our actions. good or bad.
can affect our future lives.
And why would that be
important in ethical discourse?
Tariq. enlighten us.
Well. it provides. you know.
incentive for moral action.
Karma is the law
of cause and effect.
Exactly.
You know. I was just thinking
- how interesting...
- I think you can
dig deeper. Tariq.
Karma's
basically if you do dirt.
then you get it right back.
- Yeah. and then...
- Please.
I am interested
in Tariq's perspective.
Professor. I'm not sure
what you're looking for.
And neither do I.
Professor Milgram. What's...
Karma means you cannot
escape your sins
no matter how fast
or far you may run.
They'll always catch up to you.
Don't you agree. Tariq?
Seems like Professor Milgram
had a point
to prove with you today.
Yeah. I don't know what
that was about.
That shit was weird.
You wanna go back to
your spot and grab your stuff?
I can grab my car.
Nah. it's-it's fine.
We can go straight there.
Wait.
Isn't that Zeke?
I'm surprised he didn't get
arrested after that interview.
- Yeah. you know...
- Tariq.
Come here.
I was looking for you.
- Who's that?
- That's Zeke's aunt.
She probably here to talk to me
about his tutoring and shit
now that he's back.
I gotta go. all right?
Wait. what about the apartment?
It's fine. I'ma call you later.
Let's take a drive.
What was the first thing
I said to you
when we got
into business together?
That this doesn't touch Zeke.
I'm glad you remember.
So you wanna tell me
why. of all people.
I had to hear from Cane
that you was the one
that shot the professor
they was looking at Zeke for?
- See. look it's not like that.
- Really?
Tell me what it's like. Tariq.
Look. I don't know
what Cane told you.
but that Professor Reynolds
nigga. he knew way too much.
He figured out
all this shit about GTG
once that nigga died
in the pool.
Cane heard him say Dru's name.
lost it and shot him.
I just cleaned up the mess.
I asked you right to your face
did you know anything about
that murder.
and you lied to me.
You and Cane was gonna let Zeke
hang for that shit.
No. I wasn't lettin'
Zeke hang for nothin'.
I was the one
that got Davis MacLean
involved with this shit.
Yeah. you can say
whatever you want now.
but how I'ma know
if you lyin' again?
♪ ♪
Look. Monet. my plan
was supposed to work. kay?
Ramirez was supposed to
take the fall for that shit.
I didn't know about Zeke
and my professor.
I had no idea the police
would even look into Zeke.
If they ain't let Zeke go.
you'd be looking
at a bullet right now.
I should still shoot your ass
for wasting my time.
But we need each other.
So if we gonna get past this.
I'ma need you to earn
my respect back right now.
I'll do anything.
I need you to find out
who Cane's connect is.
Get me a name.
and I'll let this go.
And if Cane finds out
what you doing.
I'ma know you two
were up to some shit...
and the gun won't stay
on my lap next time.
You feel me?
Now. find your way back.
The book is about
Tariq St. Patrick.
It's a one-to-one.
Listen. if it's a one-to-one.
doesn't that make
Zeke the main character?
I mean. he's the one fucking
the professor in the book.
No. Jabari thought
I was sleeping with Tariq.
Jabari's drug dealer character
is Tariq... I'm sure of it.
St. Patrick's father
was rumored to be
- a major player in the game.
- Look. the details
of the book... they don't match.
All the interviews
of the other kids
who got picked up in the sting...
They all said the campus
dealer was white.
Well. what if he was working
with his roommate. Brayden?
Brayden Weston?
Why would that kid
need to sell drugs?
And even if this
St. Patrick is selling drugs.
why would he kill Reynolds?
He doesn't have motive like
some other students might have.
Well. if Jabari got
close to proving it was Tariq.
maybe Tariq found out.
wanted to shut him up.
No. then not only
would we have to connect
St. Patrick to the drugs.
we'd have to prove
he knew about the book.
You got any evidence for that?
Isn't that your job?
Gotta get somethin' on the wire.
The wire is key.
That's how we connect
this kid to the operation.
That's if it turns up
something solid.
Tariq admitted everything
you said today.
but I can't just shut my
business down without a plan.
Wait. so you ain't
gon' do shit to him?
I shoulda got rid
of both of your asses
for what you did.
but I'm giving you a chance
for comin' clean
and because y'all connect.
So if I'ma keep you around.
you gotta prove to me that
this'll never happen again.
Tariq or no Tariq.
I need to trust you.
You can trust me. Ma.
Good.
I need to find out
Tariq's weaknesses.
He lied to me
because he's comfortable.
He's not afraid.
I need to know
what will hurt him.
If I can control him.
this type a shit'll
never happen again.
Can I trust you to find out?
I got you.
Good.
Lauren. I was just
about to email you.
Look. Professor Milgram.
I don't think I can
wear this wire anymore.
I don't think
that's possible at this point.
What?
Lauren. I'm gonna
tell you something
that I shouldn't.
and it stays in this room. okay?
Okay.
Some of the other students
from the sting
identified a preppy white kid
as the drug supplier.
The cops think
it's Brayden Weston.
Wait. Brayden?
Okay. so then what about
- Tariq?
They don't think
Tariq was involved.
Okay. well. you said
these drugs were tied up
into Professor Reynolds' murder.
So you think Braden
got him killed?
Well. maybe not intentionally.
Jabari was looking into
the drugs operation
for his new book.
If Brayden found out.
maybe he told the wrong person.
I mean...
That's crazy.
Brayden seems harmless.
I have to tell Tariq
to stay away from him.
I don't want him
to get in trouble.
- No.
- Yes. I have to.
If you do that
and he tells Brayden.
you would be
in a lot of trouble.
and Tariq would be
your accomplice.
You can protect Tariq
by getting more info on Brayden
and everything he knows
onto the wire.
If the police find out what
Brayden thought Jabari knew.
it will really help them
figure out what happened.
- I don't know.
- Lauren.
the faster you do this.
the faster you lose the wire.
and you and Tariq
will be free and clear.
It's up to you.
I know you'll make
the right choice.
Hey. you might wanna
give it a minute. my guy.
Bro. you gotta stop
showing up like that.
Listen. man. you ain't
been answering my texts.
So I figured
I'd just pull up on you.
see where you been at myself.
You ain't been gettin' nervous
about last night. have you?
No. I just had class. I'm cool.
Good. good. Tariq still
ain't hit me back yet.
I'm gettin' real tired
of coming to this campus
lookin' for him. Where's he at?
Honestly. I have no idea.
I haven't talked to him
since yesterday.
Maybe with his girl?
Huh.
Lauren. funny seeing you here.
Your room's just down
the hall now.
- Is Tariq here?
- He. uh...
Tariq's pretty popular.
How you doin'. light skin?
Who's your friend. Brayden?
I'm Lorenzo.
Why. you lookin'
for a new friend?
No. I'm not.
And how do you know Tariq?
I don't. but he knows
my cousin Z.
Oh. yeah. I just saw Tariq
talking with Zeke's aunt.
That's your mom?
Yeah. You know where they went?
No. I don't. I'm sorry.
But he should be back soon
'cause we're supposed to be
looking for apartments so...
Oh. he's looking
for an apartment.
- He's moving.
- Hey. Lorenzo. um...
you know. I was gonna go to
lunch. maybe grab a burger.
It's on me. I'm paying.
and then if we see Tariq.
we'll just let you know.
No. how 'bout you just
give me your digits.
and I call you
if I see the nigga?
Thanks. Brayden.
Of course.
What the fuck?
Mr. St. Patrick.
What brings you here?
My sister's custody hearing
is tomorrow.
Estelle pushed forward.
and I need you to represent me.
I can pay.
I can't do that.
I filed that complaint
with the court
on Yasmine's behalf
because your grandmother
was misusing funds.
but I'm an impartial party.
My sole job is to represent
your father's estate.
Okay. so isn't making
sure his daughter's safe
part of that interest?
If my dad asked you
to take care of his kids.
isn't this part of it?
Yes. but Tariq.
you are too young
to be someone's guardian.
Look. I just wanna take
care of my sister. all right?
You know how much
she's been through?
This is the only way.
All right. I'll represent you.
but solely on the basis
of your grandmother's
misapplication of funds.
Besides that. I'm not
stepping over any lines.
So if you can completely fulfill
all the requirements
for custody by tomorrow.
I'll give my positive
recommendation to the court.
All right. Tomorrow 3:00 p.m.
I'll be there.
You make sure
you're on time. young man.
I will. 3:00 p.m.
Look... set it up like you said.
but she already knew
what was goin' down.
Hell. I thought she'd give me
some kind of leeway
for coming clean. but...
Tch.
Hey. it's me. Talk to me. fam.
I don't know. man.
She just ain't take
all that anger out on Tariq
like I thought she would.
Now I gotta prove myself?
I just don't understand
why she ain't come down
- on this nigga like she did me.
- Right.
So that thing your cousin
almost went down for.
that was... that was you
and Tariq did that?
Whoa. nah. hey.
I ain't say all that.
You don't have to. Cane?
You're not the type of guy
to go down for somebody else.
So if you were planning
on running to save Zeke.
that means you did it.
Now. I don't know.
it seems to me
like Monet's trying to figure
out what she wants to do.
Right now she can't do shit.
because you are her plug.
That makes you indispensable.
Without you. her whole
business falls apart. man.
Yeah. but shit don't work
without Tariq either.
I don't know about that.
Anybody can find
corner boys. Cane.
But without supply.
nobody is gettin' high.
So if she's givin' you a chance
to show and prove.
be the right option...
Give her no choice.
Do not... I repeat...
Do not let her pick Tariq.
Even if you have
to force her hand. hmm?
I'm happy for Zeke.
I'm not sayin' that.
But now that he's back.
I'm back down number two
on the team
and-and maybe second round
for NBA scouts.
I didn't know you even
wanted to go into the draft
this year.
I was thinking about it.
So you leavin' New York?
I mean.
now I got reasons to stay. hmm?
♪ Baby. I'm comfortable ♪
♪ I'm comfortable ♪
♪ Tell me what you want ♪
Yo. Ev. open up.
♪ I want it too.
I want it too... ♪
Answer it.
Yo. how you like me now?
Oh. switched it up
with the hair I see. man.
Yeah. I'm switching up
everything
now that I'm a free man
and teams calling me again.
Dru. what you doin' here?
I ain't seen you
since they let me go.
And Monet brought you
right back to school. huh?
Yeah. cuz.
What the fuck is going
on with your hair. man?
Look. Freaky Zeke back. huh?
Nah. nah. nah.
No freaky Zeke. Not anymore.
You know. this whole
murder case thing.
it really got
my head on straight.
I'ma be about my business
now on my own shit.
You know what I mean?
Do what I wanna do.
not what everybody tell me.
even Aunty Monet.
I feel you.
- I feel that.
- Yeah.
You good though. Zeke?
I ain't never been better.
You know. they just said
I ain't have to go in.
somethin' about no evidence.
and I bounced.
- Ooh. congrats. man.
- Thank you.
You know who they
looking at now?
Nah. uh. I don't.
I... and honestly. I don't care.
All I know is
I get to get back out there.
play with the fellas.
and I could hit that draft.
You know. get into the league.
How y'all know each other?
Oh. shit. We met at the club.
Y-you know. the night
we all wanna forget?
Oh. yo. yo. don't even
bring that shit up.
Hey. I'ma go show
my new look to the ladies.
- Ah.
- Good to see you. cuzo.
- You too.
- Ev.
- Hey. my man.
- My man.
See you later.
Whoo!
You lie real easy.
You want me
to tell him the truth?
I didn't think so.
Now. c'mon. Playin' or what?
A'ight. I'm here.
What's so urgent?
Di. I need you
to do me a favor. all right?
I need to get some product
without Monet knowing.
Why?
It's hard to explain
right now. okay. Di?
Just... just trust me. okay?
I said why. Tariq?
Zeke is home.
Monet won't explain how.
and now you hit me up
trying to go around her?
Nah. what's going on?
A'ight. look.
I need to get money
to get my sister
out of foster care.
I got a family court
hearing tomorrow.
My grandmother got a DWI.
so my sister can't stay
with her anymore.
Damn. A'ight. so what
are you gonna do?
I mean. only thing I can do
is try to get custody
of her myself.
I gotta pay for a lawyer.
and I got to put a deposit
on this fucking apartment.
so it's a lot.
And Monet. she shut down
CourseCorrect
'cause she don't trust me. so...
I don't know
what the fuck to do.
I mean. I would ask Cane.
but I don't trust
that nigga either.
So I need you to ask him for me.
Okay. I'll help you
on one condition.
Anything. Talk to me.
Tariq. I don't trust Cane
right now either.
So I need to find out
what he's doing.
Look. we already know
Cane killed Ramirez.
So Ramirez's gun showing up
at the professor's murder scene
while Zeke is under suspicion?
I don't know. but that shit
don't sit right with me.
Yeah. I-I feel you for sure.
Yeah. but even before that.
I was pretty sure Cane switched
the coke with sugar
when Effie and Brayden
got jumped at Yale.
You know. that actually
makes a lot of fucking sense.
because he's the plug now.
Exactly.
Look. if you find
anything out about Cane.
I need you to tell me. a'ight?
Anything.
I got you.
Don't even worry about it.
A'ight.
Tariq is hiding
his business from Monet?
For what?
Listen. I'm not doing shit
until I know.
He needs money for his sister.
Cane. he's got
a custody hearing tomorrow.
and he needs money
to pay a lawyer
and to get a place to stay.
So? Sounds like a him problem.
It might be.
but I might make it
a you problem
if I tell Monet you're the one
who sugared the coke.
You know. when you wanted
back in with the family.
Why the fuck
would you say all that?
Why wouldn't I?
You acting just like Monet.
thinking you know shit.
puttin' niggas
under pressure with fake news.
Fake news? A'ight.
Well. how about
I tell Monet myself
and let her decide
if you did it or not.
Okay. damn. I'll handle it.
Uh... what?
- I'll do it.
- Right.
By tonight. Cane.
I'll handle it.
Just make sure he comes
to get the product himself.
All right.
Who's your friend. Brayden?
My name's Lorenzo.
Why. you looking
for a new friend?
Who's this other guy. Lorenzo?
I thought he was gonna
be involved with the drugs.
but I was wrong... he's just
the cousin of Zeke Cross.
Cross' cousin
knows this Brayden kid?
He wasn't there for Brayden.
He was there for Brayden's
roommate. Tariq St. Patrick.
Tariq tutors Zeke.
Wait a second.
Where's the rest of the tape?
They went out. so I left.
Excuse me.
Lauren.
you may need to be
a little more aggressive.
Reason being we're gonna
upgrade your device
so we can listen live and coach
you on some questions.
What?
No. I don't want to do that.
Lauren. we're getting closer.
I need you to be brave.
What else do you know
about Brayden and the guys
he hangs out with?
Kamaal. I need a second.
Excuse me. ladies.
- What's this?
- Cousin Lorenzo.
Full name is Lorenzo Tejada Jr.
Goes by a childhood nickname.
Cane.
He's got a few misdemeanors.
Some violent offenses
that got knocked down.
So you think this kid's
suspicious.
If that Zeke's cousin.
he doesn't need Ramirez. right?
Maybe Zeke gets his cousin
to pop the cop
and take out the professor.
We have no proof of that
or even a motive
on why he'd want Ramirez dead.
We're not getting much
from this Lauren kid either.
This is a lead.
Honestly.
I think that we need to
take Tariq St. Patrick
more seriously.
Maybe Carrie's right that
he and this Brayden kid
are dealing drugs.
Still doesn't give us
motive if Tariq or Brayden
doesn't know
what the professor knew. okay?
Let's look into this Cane.
It's solid.
Yeah. okay.
Look into it. but we cannot
take it to Jenny.
Not yet.
- Course.
- All right.
The cops are not
looking at Zeke no more.
There was a press conference
and everything... he's free.
See. Mo. I told you
it would work out.
Cops had no reason to hold him.
Just had to have
a little faith and wait it out.
Yeah.
I guess I shoulda had faith.
Mr. Tejada. this is Cooper Saxe.
I'm the attorney your daughter
hired to help free you.
We have a hearing tomorrow.
Can you speak freely?
Yeah. give me a moment.
I gotta take this. Mo.
Deadass?
A'ight.
Mr. Saxe.
Yeah. man. I can tell you
anything you need to know.
Where is Kamaal?
Ha.
Oh. you gotta be kidding me.
You're bypassing
your babysitter?
I know that Cross
wasn't the shooter
in those murders.
but I know
he's involved in this.
Do you have
any evidence for that?
Because I just held a press
conference that said otherwise.
I been looking into his family.
He's got an uncle in jail.
So we know the uncle
didn't do it.
And a cousin with a rap sheet.
"Lorenzo Tejada Jr.
Nickname... Cane."
Zeke's close with the Tejadas?
Close enough to live with him
during his high school years.
And it also happens
that the. uh.
the family lives in
the dead cop's precinct.
I may need more than this
to get Cross back involved.
After that
press conference fiasco.
I'm gonna need
a bulletproof case against him
and this Cane Tejada.
♪ ♪
Come on. Let's go. Your place.
- Who's that guy?
- Nobody. Let's go.
Told my sister Tariq
needed to be here himself
for this little off-grid deal
to go down.
Look. bro.
I just go where I'm told.
Where's he at anyway?
Still don't know?
Your guess is good as mine.
Okay.
Hey. what does he need
all this for?
Y'all just picked up
not that long ago.
Do you think
he tells me anything?
I don't know. nigga.
You said
y'all was equal partners.
Am I right?
You're still getting paid.
I don't know what the issue is.
♪ Caution. you
Niggas playin' the horses ♪
♪ My niggas playin'
With locals ♪
♪ I'm out here
Runnin' this office ♪
♪ I'ma recruit 'em
And tell 'em to shoot 'em ♪
♪ You already know you already
Know where my armor ♪
♪ You and the drama with
Niggas that don't like it ♪
♪ I'ma just be real honest ♪
♪ We're good to stay
On the block ♪
♪ We know that tension Is high ♪
♪ It could be 20 below.
If you frontin' ♪
♪ And makin' the temperature
Rise ♪
♪ They know who really gon'
slide ♪
♪ I'll be actin'
Like I ain't no demon ♪
♪ They know when they
Look in my eyes ♪
♪ I will remember A long time ♪
♪ Hopin' I slip.
It's a long line ♪
♪ Thought I was free.
Got more time ♪
♪ Leave with the team
When he caught nine ♪
♪ Part of the team when he
Caught his first body ♪
♪ I mean. I wanted to ask ♪
♪ How 'bout a bar
With this tat ♪
♪ I got a farmer inside
Of a farmer tonight ♪
♪ With a buck on a dash ♪
♪ Lady been cuttin' The grass ♪
♪ I gotta watch For the snakes ♪
♪ I'll put a hit on your ass ♪
♪ I'm just as hot
As they think. well ♪
♪ Who you?
Boy. we don't know you ♪
♪ You in the car. what?
♪ Now we ain't doin'
The tough talk ♪
♪ But we assure you
But we assure you ♪
♪ So it's green light.
Boy we adore you ♪
♪ Go go go go ♪
♪ Who you?
Boy. we don't know you ♪
♪ You in the car. what?
♪ Now we ain't doin'
The tough talk ♪
♪ But we assure you ♪
What you need?
Delivery for Mecca.
What the fuck. yo?
Looking for something?
I wasn't looking for shit. man.
I was just making a call.
I swear.
What's up. Nuff?
Caught someone spyin' on us.
Man. I wasn't spying on shit.
Who the fuck is that?
That one of Mahoney's boys?
Keep him still.
Get off me. I ain't do anything!
I ain't see anything
What?
You know him?
No. I don't know him.
You hear that?
Does not look good for you.
You ain't got no friends here.
You sure it's not
another one of your friends?
Nuff has never been good
at stopping once he starts.
Look. I just said I never
seen the little nigga
before in my life.
Let him go.
Now. Nuff.
Get the fuck outta here.
F...
Fuck!
Oh. my God. what happened?
Is Monet here?
I need to talk to her.
Look. I don't know
where she is... I'm here alone.
Here. c-come inside.
♪ Had to risk it all ♪
Um. you sh...
You should. uh.
you should go home.
- I'll call you later.
- Yeah. I'll call you later.
- Yo. what's going on here?
- Just get some bandages. Dru.
Shit.
I don't think he was
one of Mahoney's crew.
He wouldn't have sent him
alone and unarmed.
Mecca. I handled it.
Ain't no way that skinny punk
come back for another ass
whooping.
But... he did show up
right when you did.
You sure you ain't bring him?
That true?
Yeah. he could have
been following him.
but Cane said
he didn't know him.
How we know
it ain't another one of
his little friends?
I got this phone off him but...
Cane. did you know him?
You let him follow you here?
Nah. I didn't.
Okay.
What?
You just gon'
take his word for it?
If you didn't know
he was with Mahoney.
you should've never put your
fucking hands on that kid.
One civilian complaint. Nuff.
puts us all at risk.
Now look at you.
You know. he always
did talk too much
for somebody expendable.
Clean this up.
So I saw you clear that
basketball player on the news.
He really ain't do it?
'Cause his interview... ooh!
Was a mess.
That's the problem
with innocent clients.
They're not prepared to lie.
What do you want. Davis?
I got a knitting circle
I gotta get back to.
Really? A knitting circle?
All right.
The white boy I hired
is working on an appeal
for one of our clients.
Very similar circumstances
to yours.
Manslaughter. buncha eye
witnesses. long rap sheet.
Yeah. yeah.
Hey. hey. if he gets
this guy out.
I'm gonna pivot him
right to you.
Are you. uh. you sure
you wanna do this. bro?
'Cause I'm all right in here.
I mean that.
Things could come out. you know.
Not the way
I'ma have my boy play it.
I will do anything
to get you out.
And I would do anything
to keep you out.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
I apologize for being late.
I was in traffic.
Yes.
Well. the apartment's
no longer available.
What?
Tariq. where have you been?
Why haven't you been
answering your phone.
and what happened to your face?
Are you okay?
Yeah. I got robbed.
but I'm fine.
Lauren. I need to talk to her.
I need this place.
Okay.
Well. she's not coming back.
She was already on the fence
before you showed up
looking like this.
I-I don't know what to do.
The court's not gonna
give me custody of Yas
if I don't show them
proof of a place to stay.
I'm fucked!
Okay. look.
I think I have an idea.
Come on.
This is my brother's spot.
I was gonna offer it
to you before.
but I know you're not
the best at taking help.
I mean... doesn't
your brother need this?
Um... he hasn't been able
to live outside of
a halfway house for a while.
But my parents gave me the keys
for when he's back.
so how about we say it's not
forever but for right now.
I... I don't even know
what to say. Lauren. like...
Tariq. it's okay.
I really wanna help you
and your sister be together.
Let me show you around.
So this pulls out into a bed.
and then there's
a bedroom over there.
Thank you.
I really appreciate
you doing this for me.
Thank you for letting me do it.
Oh. wait.
Here.
You're gonna need a lease
for your custody case.
You know. if you live here.
you wouldn't have to stay
with Brayden anymore.
I mean. I don't know.
Staying with Brayden
ain't that bad. He's cool.
I know. but...
don't you think it was weird
how happy he was
when Professor Reynolds died?
Offering all those girls
a shoulder to cry on?
No. Look. Brayden didn't even
know Professor Reynolds
until I told him about him.
All right? So honestly I don't
even know why he would care.
Yeah. I mean maybe.
but Professor Reynolds
probably knew who Brayden was.
He's very visible as a Weston.
And what about that book
Professor Reynolds was writing?
You don't think
that was about Brayden?
Look. no.
That book was definitely
not about Brayden.
Are you sure?
Yes. Professor Reynolds
told me who it was about.
On top of that.
that nigga only wrote about
Black people anyway. so...
So not Brayden?
No.
Reynolds told him
what the book was about.
Yeah. which means
it's probably not about him.
That means
Carrie's reaching again.
Tariq was listed
as one of the students
Reynolds saw the day
he was murdered.
And I looked into
Tariq's Choate record.
He was living with
Weston way back then
and he was expelled for drugs.
If Tariq is the Stansfield link
to the drug operation
and knew Reynolds was writing
about it. that's motive.
Why would Reynolds
tell St. Patrick
that he was going to
expose him in his book?
Doesn't even make
any fucking sense.
Much less. it's not enough
for a warrant.
It's enough
for Stansfield to open up
Tariq's dorm
so we can look around.
- What's this?
- It's what you wanted.
It's Tariq's phone.
He has a custody hearing
tomorrow at 3:00.
For his sister.
They could've killed us both
for what you did.
Yeah. I know what you did.
Sending Tariq to follow me
to the connect.
I'm not stupid. Monet.
No matter how many times
you say that to me.
All this time I'm out here
blaming Tariq for everything.
But it's clear to me now
you're the problem.
I'm here really thinking
you was gonna let me back in.
but you was gonna play me
like you play him.
like you play all of us...
You're a fucking joke.
Boy. I didn't fucking
make you kill Ramirez
or Reynolds.
I do whatever
I fuckin' need to do
to make sure this family
and this business don't fall.
But that's the fucking problem!
It's always family
and fucking business.
What am I to you. huh?
Your soldier
or your fucking son?
You're both.
Then what kind of fucking
mother does that make you?
Make sure Tariq gets his phone.
Get in.
Monet. I can't talk right now.
I got my sister's hearing.
I'm tired of playing
with you. Tariq.
You failed.
Cane wasn't 'posed to find out
what you was doing.
Listen. I didn't tell Cane.
I-I got caught following him.
And when you got caught.
did you call me?
No.
So these are the
consequences of your actions.
You never think the dirt
that you do
is gonna come back to you.
So we gonna sit here and
wait 'til you lose your sister
like I almost lost Zeke.
Shouldn't take long.
Look. I got information. right?
I got a address. I got a name.
The name is Mecca.
I can get more.
Mecca and an address. That's it?
Look. let me go. and I can
get you more information.
That's it.
Nah. I can't let you go. Tariq.
See. this is your consequence
with Zeke
and for breaking our rules
so this doesn't happen again.
Now you know
I'm the one in control.
You feel me?
You know. you're wrong.
You think you in control.
but you on a island
and you don't even know it.
Boy. you better watch your step
before you say some shit
you can't take back.
So. you... you really think
you could do this shit
without me? Half of the shit
going on under your nose.
you don't even see it.
Cane. he replaced Rico's work
with sugar
just to get you
to take him back.
Dru. he's still fucking
that nigga
that dropped him
and Zeke's name to the school
about that dead body
in the pool.
And Diana...
Diana stole that money
out your bar.
You can't do none of this shit
without me.
You need me.
and I need my sister.
So what are we doing?
My client is here. Your Honor.
You're late. Mr. St. Patrick.
I'd like to reopen
the issue of granting him
custody rather than sending
the child into foster care.
I don't see
how your client being here
changes the fact that he's
barely an adult. Mr. Warren.
and that he looks like
he's just been in a brawl.
I'm inclined to keep
the child in foster care
until her
grandmother's completed
the requisite recovery program.
I understand your concerns.
Your Honor.
but my client's circumstances
are not those of
the average teenager.
He has shown time and time
again that he is willing
and able to step into a role
far beyond his years
and that he cares deeply
for his sister.
I. therefore. beg the court
to reconsider.
And by the way.
while I have no doubt
that Ms. Green
feels the same way.
unfortunately. she has misused
money from the trust fund.
Tariq can provide stability
until Ms. Green has recovered.
Surely. a family member
is better than state care.
Your Honor. I just...
I just wanna
keep my family together.
You know. my baby sister
is all I have.
I mean. I have
everything together.
I have an apartment.
Everything is there on the file.
Only thing I don't have
is a chance.
He's a baby. Your Honor.
He can't raise a baby.
Did you use the child's funds
to support a drinking habit?
I admit my drinking
got away from me. Your Honor.
but I'm better now.
Have you completed
a rehabilitation program?
No. but I have prayed on it.
Your Honor.
Your Honor. I can pay
for my grandmother
to go to rehab. all right?
I love... I love my grandmother.
but she's just not in Yasmin's
best interest right now.
Circumstances for this family
have been very. very hard
and they just getting harder.
I want my grandmother
to be strong enough.
and she will be in the future.
but I'm strong enough now.
and I can take this
responsibility for my sister.
I'll grant you custody
on a temporary basis.
- but one misstep...
- Ughh!
And I'll be forced to remand
the child back into state care.
Don't test me. Mr. St. Patrick.
Thank you. Your Honor.
- Thank you.
- Congratulations.
There's nothing here.
Well. then you need
to vacate now.
Hold on.
Now. what were you sayin'?
I led my kids down
the wrong path. Dante.
They don't trust me.
they don't trust each other.
Fuck. I thought I was
teaching them the life.
Making them strong.
Shit.
Maybe we do need a fresh start.
Maybe I do too.
Maybe I could meet Zeke now.
if you're ready.
I need some time.
Let me speak to my kids.
but I think so.
Yes.
Hey...
♪ I just wanna Love you baby ♪
Anything you need.
Anything.
♪ Baby 'cause you got me
So fucked up ♪
♪ All for you. babe You. babe ♪
♪ You. babe. you babe ♪
♪ You. babe ♪
We see your brother.
and it's all gonna
be okay. all right?
Look. here he is.
- Thank you.
- Sure. I'll be in touch.
Told you you was
gonna come home with me.
Listen. I'ma go set up
the apartment for you
and then in a little bit you
can come stay with me. okay?
Listen. Yas. Grandma
loves you. all right?
She's just going through
a lot right now.
Gonna get her some help and
we'll be a family again. okay?
Okay. Tariq. I trust you.
You should. I got you.
Tariq St. Patrick.
you are under arrest.
- What?
- For the murders
of Officer Danilo Ramirez
and Professor Jabari Reynolds.
What the fuck?
Tariq.
Let him go. Lauren.
It's what he deserves.
♪ I believe what I sell ♪
♪ Why does everyone
Hear me wrong? ♪
♪ If I told you different.
Would it sound the same? ♪
♪ Would it make a difference
In any way? ♪
♪ Oh oh ♪
♪ I know I done wrong.
I'll pay for it ♪
♪ It's your turn to talk
For once I'm listenin' ♪
♪ Say that you don't want me ♪
♪ Say that you don't need me ♪
♪ Tell me I'm the fool ♪
♪ Tell me you've been Tortured ♪
♪ Tell me you've been beaten ♪
♪ And what I've done to you ♪
♪ Even if it doesn't matter ♪
♪ Matter what's true ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Look at all this heartache ♪
Hello. This is he.
- Taxi!
- ♪ Forgetting how it started ♪
♪ This is how it ends ♪
♪ Oh. no. I know
I done some wrong ♪
♪ I'll pay for it ♪
♪ But it's your turn
To talk... ♪
Your lawyer's here. Get up.
♪ Say that you don't want me ♪
♪ Say that you don't need me ♪
♪ Tell me I'm the fool ♪
♪ Tell me you've been Tortured ♪
♪ Tell me you've been beaten ♪
♪ And what I've done to you... ♪
So... I received word
of your arrest
shortly after the hearing today.
What is this?
I actually
don't know what's inside.
Only that I was supposed
to give it to you in the event
that you were arrested
for homicide.
It's from your father.
I had actually hoped.
Mr. St. Patrick.
that I would never
have to give that to you.
♪ I believe what I say ♪
♪ Why does everyone
Hear me wrong? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I know I done wrong.
I'll pay for it ♪
♪ It's your turn to talk ♪
♪ For once I'll listen... ♪
I knew you'd
end up here. lil nigga.
Right where you belong.
♪ Say that you don't need me ♪
♪ Tell me I'm the fool ♪
♪ Tell me that I'm unknown oh ♪
♪ To you ♪
Mo.
I'm home.
I'm home. baby.
Ma. how did you
keep this a secret?
This why you been
acting so weird?
Yeah. I guess I... didn't
wanna ruin the surprise.
♪ I got a little For the low ♪
♪ We can take it
To the table. break it down ♪
♪ Just don't hurt The block ♪
♪ Ain't nothin'
But a stuck door ♪
♪ You can take it to
The block and sweat ♪
♪ Or rock the rug.
We get money over here ♪
♪ We the hustlers of the year ♪
♪ You want it.
You can get it get it ♪
♪ We won't stop
I get a lift for the 46 ♪
♪ 23 for the half. If you want ♪
♪ Ain't suckers for nobody
Where the money at ♪
♪ Where dem 20s. where dem 50s.
Where them hundreds at ♪
♪ Duffle bag. boy ♪
♪ Black door.
Number's on the low low ♪
♪ Come true.
Tend it up like a po po ♪
♪ Rolling on my wrists
For some bullshit ♪
♪ 440 on my head
Yeah worth a shit ♪
♪ Street sweep. Finger block ♪
♪ We gon' get this
Motherfucker Belsin ♪
♪ I might sell some love
Someone else's ♪
♪ Take it to the scale.
Weigh it like a whale ♪
♪ That block. let's rock ♪
♪ I told you niggas We on top ♪
♪ Now we in an after hour
takin' shots ♪
♪ Doublin' the bottles baby.
It's not a problem baby ♪
♪ We got it ♪
♪ Work the block yeah ♪
♪ Work the block
I got it in for the low ♪
♪ We can take it to the table
Break it down ♪
♪ Just don't hurt the block ♪
♪ Ain't nothin' but
A stuck door ♪
♪ We can take it to The block ♪
♪ Sweat or rock the rug ♪
♪ We get money over here ♪
♪ We the hustlers Of the year ♪
♪ You want it you can
Get it get it ♪
♪ We won't stop ♪
♪ Hold on. We hustlers baby ♪
♪ You get too close.
I don't trust ya baby ♪